Guide to the Turkish Elections Political Ephemera, 2018 RL.11743
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Turkish elections political ephemera
2018
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11743
1 Linear Feet
The collection consists of printed ephemera documenting the 2018 presidential election in Turkey. Represented in the collection are the major parties, including the Justice and Development Party (AKP), Peoples' Democratic Party (HDP), Republican People's Party (CHP), Nationalist Movement Party (MDP), Felicity Party (Saadet), Patriotic Party (Vatan), and Iyi Party (Iyi). Materials are in Turkish.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into series by election year, and within each election year by political party.
Biographical / Historical
Presidential, parliamentary, and general elections were held throughout Turkey on 24 June 2018.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Turkish Elections Political Ephemera collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2018.
Related Materials
Addition materials relating to 15 Temmuz, the failed coup d'etat attempt of 15 July 2016, are available in the Turkish Political Posters Collection: https://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/turkishpostercoll/
Collection Overview
The collection consists of printed ephemera documenting the 2018 presidential election in Turkey. Represented in the collection are the major parties, including the Justice and Development Party (AKP), Peoples' Democratic Party (HDP), Republican People's Party (CHP), Nationalist Movement Party (MDP), Felicity Party (Saadet), Patriotic Party (Vatan), and Iyi Party (Iyi). Materials are in Turkish.
Turkey -- Politics and government; Elections -- Turkey; Political parties -- Turkey
- 2018 Presidential and General Elections, 1
  - Milliyetçi Hareket Partisi (MHP), 1
    - One page leaflet of candidates with biographies across 7 different pieces (Box 1)
    - Cumhur İttifakı Millet Aklı, 30 p. (on the MHP-AKP agreement) 1 pc. (Box 1)
    - Seçim Beyannamesi, 14 p. 1 pc. (Box 1)
    - Yurtiçi Sandık Kurulu Görevlileri Genelgesi, 47 p. 1 pc. (Box 1)
    - Devlet Bahçeli, Cumhurbaşkanlığı Hükümet Sistemine Geçiş Süreci Yeni Ruh, Ortak Akıl, Milli Şuur (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Vols. I-II-III set, 174+238+183 pp.
    - Cumhur İttifakı Millet Aklı, Milli Diriliş Kutlu Yükseliş, Milliyetçi Hareket Partisi Seçim Beyannamesi, Ankara, 129 p. (Box 1)
  - Vatan Partisi, 2
    - Seçim Bildirgesi, 32 p. (Box 1)
    - Çözüm Perinçek, leaflet (Box 1)
  - İyi Parti, 3
    - Leaflet (Box 1)
    - İyi Türkiye Bir Yakın Dönem Siyasetnamesi, 56 p. (Box 1)
    - Leaflet of Meral Akşener (Box 1)
    - Leaflet, Yüzünü Güneşe Dön Türkiye, 4 p. (Box 1)
  - Saadet Partisi (SP), 4
    - Leaflet of Temel Karamollaoğlu, Presidential Candidate (Box 1)
    - Declaration of Temel Karamollaoğlu 4 p., newspaper size (Box 1)
  - Cumhuriyet Halk Partisi (CHP), 5
    - Leaflet of presidential candidate Muharrem İnce (Box 1)
    - 3 different leaflets (Box 1)
    - Millet İçin Geliyoruz! Seçim Bildirgesi 2018, 226 p. (Box 1)
    - Cumhuriyet Halk Partisi Tüzük (9-10 Mart 2018 Tarihli 19. Olağanüstü Kurultayda Kabul Edilmiştir), Ankara, 91 p. (Box 1)
  - Adalet ve Kalkınma Partisi (AKP), 6
    - 6 different leaflets (Box 1)
    - İşimiz Hizmet Gücümüz Millet, AK Parti, Ankara, Februray 2018 (Box 2)
      3 volume set in a box, 469+409+499 total 1377 p., 4,5 kg.
    - Cumhurbaşkanımız Sn. Recep Tayyip Erdoğan'ın 24 Haziran 2018 Seçimleri Manifestosu, 38 p. (Box 1)
  - Halkların Demokratik Partisi (HDP), 7
    - 4 different leaflets (Box 2)
  - Non Governmental Organizations, 8
    - Bir Adım Daha (Box 2)
    - Beyoğlu Yurttaşlar Meclisi (Box 2)
    - Orhan Aydın (Box 2)